What afternoon everyone?
I'm nervous xml program manager in visual studio team.
And, today we will talk about developing universal windows app in visual studio two
...fifty.
...drawing the draw going on so if you-get-a-chance
...strongly committed to evaluate this shown your feedback helps us
...so...please definitely addendum...evaluate and...your feedback.
And, still.
Are very for...formal confirmation from seattle
I'm waiting on of text on my phone but ...new windows tend
os slide and windows ten tools for universal windows app
development of will be going live rightnow so at the end of
this session please go and download your windows ten
...flight which is ten dot all dot hundred-seventy five-zero this is
...to...that would be published today...install your visual studio
...vid windows ten tools which are
required for developing universal windows app and then build your first universal...
right so this is going live right now they are in the chain of getting published
...the end of the...you should be able to go and download all this stuff and start building...application?
...installing visual studio make sure that you go to the custom set-up and select
universal windows are development tools and if you're interested in emulator you should select that as
about everything we're going to talk about today the require you to have universal
windows app tools installed as part of your studio if you don't have it then windows
...not be supported so as you installing visual studio go to the custom
...make sure...that jag to a wide any future surprises.
So, let's talk about the agenda and...simple.
I'm going to go and start with the introduction to windows universal platform.
And, I'm pretty sure most of you have already seen the keynote and,
...kind of outlined some of the details about us of windows platform some of you must
...also attended andrew clinics...app model chechen
he also kind of talks about how application model works and what what's the new in the you with
windows platform so I will give you a quick overview of that and after that
...deep dive into some of the visual studio two-lane that we have done to support
...windows app we have what across many different features so in my
shun I will be going and try to go as many features as possible and mostly
we'll be talking giving an overview of these features we have also schedule some deep dive
into some of the big features which I think...be very which we think we're going to be very interesting from a
...standpoint so I will be mentioning goshen and you will also find a
jail for goshen that literature sharon's flied and I recommend you guys to go
...it and those as well?
And, in the last ten fifteen minutes we will do and opencreate a and,
but, as I'm going through my talk if you feel that I'm going to fast or
to slow or if you want me to ask if you want to
...specific question about...the features that I'm talking about feel
free to raise your hand and I will try to answer data itself if not then
you can definitely hopefully I will be able to on so all the questions to was the end and ...
Cool so let's talk about you will windows platform.
Lossywhen I was here at build and we talked about windows forty-eight point one platform
and shared projects and teddy presented the plan of via he
...that of windows...device and, you release the next version of windows we'll have a unify
develop a platform and that's what we
have today like finally we have a unify developer platform
that works across all windows ten devices whether it's mobile
...desktop xbox coyote
...all the windows and devices all run on windows
stent and that's the create exciting use for a...because finally he
didn't need to think about different versions and different platforms running on different windows
...is a theme when arty platform that runs across all these windows
...devices?
For windows forty-point one if you guys remember if you
have build application the story was that there was a high degree of conversions but
...developers to build...different application package
one application package for windows eight-point one another application package for windows
forty-eight point one and they used to go to...different stores windows to revel of...to...and
...windows backbone we finally have binary compatibility you can
now use a single project to create a single application package that
...across all windows ten device.
Said that.
If you have a scenario in mind where you want
a specific package to go to a specific device family as an example
if you want a wmv windows mobile package of just say...package should only go
...windows mobile devices and you can do that as well as part of my
talk I will show you how you how that can be at on how you can do that in visual studio.
Finally if you look in the image...diagram they are the centerpiece is the
...windows platform every
api that exist in the universe of windows platform you can use
...and expected to be the on every windows
ten device right so that's the conversions.
But,...still some bits and pieces
via the awesome capabilities which are specific to a device family.
As an example let's think about mobile right there still
...phone devices that are running hardware back buttons.
So, as a developer you need to think about how exactly my application
will go and use the capabilities that are specific to
a device family and that does the place...will go in the explore what adaptive
...how you can write adaptive code and...look at some demos for that as well.
So, let's now talk about the supported os for universal windows
the development from visual studio perspective we always
...developers to be running on the highest version of windows to get the
best develop experience so-if you want-to go and...universal windows app
will encourage you to go and use the latest reduced and fly and installed tools and build
your application when you are running on windows ten you can go and
use any of these deployment targets...can run your application in a simulator
you can rugged your application on the local machine you can use the mobile emulator
...see how your application will work on a phone device you can use the remote
machine scenario to validate your
...your application on a remote pc or xbox
or an i-device and you can also use a connected phone device
...you do a ipo usb and deploy...application to a hardware
...device right so when you're running on windows...all these deployment targets are supported.
If you are...if you are you doing you are design
...then you can when you're running on windows ten you can use...design out in visual studio and
lead to actually go and implement...to see how it...application will look lent look,
at the runtime and...design our feature itself.
But, for the first-time.
Visual studio is novel support universal windows
...development on previously released version of all with as
...right so you can go and install visual studio
...thousand fifteen are fee on of windows eight-point one machine and develop
...universal windows app so if you're running on windows eight-point
one because the previous version of os the experience will be slightly degraded
as an example you cannot you will not have simulator and local machine of
the deployment target because you cannot run of windows ten application on windows eight-point
...similarly because of download design I have some
dependency that uses the runtime os to give you the
...and to render...am application so example design
...not be of level of any running on a windows eight-point one os
...will instead give you a full example editor view via example
intelligence both for platform and question type and you can use that to build your application.
At...dn will also support building
universal windows app on windows seven
right again because it's a windows seven os hyper v
is not supported so emulator will not work but you will be able to use
remote machine to actually deploy are application on of endorsed and...xbox
...and I ot and you can also use the user connected phone device to deploy
...application onto a for device and...it and debugged.
And, as I mentioned before you will not have them and design experience
in windows seven as well but you will be you able to use...right so the
message which of os you are running on what windows seven windows eight-point one of
windows server two the ventral rtwo or windows...you can go and download visual studio
are fee...universe of windows tools and start building...application.
Now let's talk a little bit about project templates do that let's actually
...is to do so.
The search tvs.
And, if I bring up the new project dialogue here.
You will see that universal windows project template are located
and visual csharp windows and windows universal node.
We have a bank application project template of which you can use
a starting point for building your application is an applicant generates
...application package other than that we have a dl
...of an artery project template...unit test project template.
You can see that we don't have any
advanced project template like hub grid a split
likely used to half of the previous version of windows platform right.
To mitigate that windows steam have actually relieved a huge
number of samples so if you want to go and learn a little bit
more about adaptive code all you want to go a little bit and learn more about
adaptive ui or if you are encrusted on learning more about...specific api
...feature you is file and find the right example on get
...that windows team has published so I'll encourage you guys to go and
explode this get up repository download the samples and
...exploring some of the new windows api...that we have added for windows...platform.
Now once you have created your
...so let's step back...studio.
And, I've just use my example application here.
So, once you have created...project and if you bring up the project
properties you will see that we have actually added some new properties
...universal windows up right here you can see that there are two properties
target version admin version if you click here you see the target version combo
...showing multiple as the case it showing one zero six nine
...is zero one zero nine zero right of similarly if you click on a
...version you will see multiple...listed
here as well so what are these properties and how a developer should think about it?
These properties...critical and for-you...up and I will explain
why let's take a look at what exactly is target what exactly is target
of version so the target version property that you see in the project properties is
...by target platform version in your project file if you one of the cs project you will
see target platform version and that's what being it's displayed in the project property what this target
platform version means it defines the worsen of universal as
...your project is being compiled
against right so it defines the api surface that is
...to your project and that's what that target version
indicates think about this as windows good into a servicing model and
start shipping more and more updates they will be different versions of universal windows
educate and different versions of universal windows platform...running on a device so-if you
want-to go and use the latest feature you will go and download the educate once you have installed
educate in the project properties you will see the educates to be listed there you can go and
change the target version to the version of...decay you want to use and start using the new
...right that's what the target version property...
As part of the build process visual studio will automatically
take the target version property and stump it into the manifest file so there's
...property...manifest file which is called target device family which names
...windows of universal...a universal package and it hasn't been version
...version tested so the target version property is page...part of the
...process
...at the map version tested in the manifest file and this goes to the store as part
your application package and os these days it uses the
...version tested to quirk and api behavior the what
...working me...a very simple statement if windows
...size to change the behavior often application in the future versions so
if you say that the version avce tested against is one zero six nine and when the
...the behavior of the api...so that the application that are running on sixty nine
davis to get the sixty nine behavior and not the latest one because you have not tested
...that that's a simple way that working works another part of the
...process will stand the target back from version as a
...version tested property in the generated manifest...part of the process?
So, what is a min version?
The min version is...by target platform inversion property
in the project file and what is signifies that minimum version
...universal windows platform you
should be running to be able to use...deployed package or run
this package right so again in the ideal world when
...shipping multiple version of the universal platform and
they are different windows ten devices running on different versions of universal
platform in an ideal world you will keep them in version to be the lowest number a
devices running...target version should be the highest version of the use of windows decay
...so that you're using all the latest and greatest
...right this minute version property as part of the...process will be stand
adam inversion in your manifest file and when store
...see this manifest file it will filter the packages based on
guzman version as an example if I'm running a device which
is running hundred-fifty version of windows...which is standard zero dot
hundred-fifty dot zero and I go and try to use this package...will not even
...that because it will see them inversion required for this package is sixty nine that
will automatically filter that so when
you're thinking about universal windows platform when you think about us of windows project and
the adaptive code these two properties become very interesting if you have developed
an android app I'm pretty sure you guys...they are they have three different versions but
he was the stories the same make sure these values of set correctly
...project file and specify visual the educate that you are using?
Now let's talk a little bit about windows device family actuation...case.
So, as I mentioned there is a we have a unify developer platform
what they are still some capabilities that exist specific to
work target device family right and we talked about hardware but...unfold.
For...allow developers to actually use these the api
...use these capabilities which are specific to a
device family we have introduce the concept of device family actuation
...right so let's actually go to...visual studio.
And, take a look at that.
So, for this one and just going to use my...
book application before we a dive into this let's actually just run
the application see what it does for you guys are familiar with it so I will go
...this application on local machine.
Okay, I'll just try to fix it...enough of...so,
my app is a very simple...application and I can just
go it's basically showing a set of categories here which of advertisers to some
...I can go and click on a specific category and if
we show you a set of recipes for that category and you can click on a recipe and
...you in instructions and ingredients for preparing that recipe?
And, you can click on a...into navigate back
this is actually using adaptive ui so you can go and actually resize the application and you
see it's actually resize it and shows produce issue the right elements of the right layout.
And, I can go back and run this same code on emulator the
same universal single project which I'm not going to go and apply to emulator.
Just to save some time have kept emulate open already and we have the same application
are running on a mobile emulator as well again, I can click on
a category and pretty much works the same way.
So, it's a seeing universal
...working on both bc as well as on mobile...
emulator but now if I go...click on the badminton you will see my application
...now this is not the best expedia is
...developer would like to provide it for the application right in the real-world when somebody pass-the-buck
button you would like the application to navigate back to the previous page.
...how less...fix that for this application and see how that would work so.
Let me see if I can increase the font-size.
Tooth auctions all right industries...that's maybe the.
...better awesome so animation hardware
...button are...part of an windows device
...educate so let's actually go and add reference to that so if I go and rightly on
...references and bring up the addresses dialogue and go into windows universal
actuation is decays you will see that they are different windows mobile
actuation is decay windows desktop...as well as coyote and
...like all different device family if they have
some additional capabilities dealership annexation is...for developer to be able to use that so you can go and
select the...is decay here and click ok.
And, pretty...exactly works like you have if you have user third-party actuation
educate the workflow is identical just go and add the
difference once you have done that visual studio and microsoft...will automatically find the right contract...
md for you and it's a start using those...is to allow you to...api than...them.
So, once
...done added the difference to mobile actuation educate I will go...you wired up my hardware back
...the right the code windows dot phone.
Dot ui dot hardware not input
Hogs impotence dot.
Blacklist.
So, as I'm doing it I want to show one of the...features is
the develop a assistant the as decay that is powered by bing
and that's recently we have shipped what this develop assistant...if as
you're writing a using a api it actually uses bing to give you a sample
cord of how this api should be used so here in the example issuing me that you get
...up your hardware back buttons and who might want to go and put it in a
...check and we'll discuss why so I'll just go and what up my?
And, generate ...
So, that's pretty much.
So, if I go
and run this code rightnow on local machine what will happen anyone.
It will crash why do crash.
Exactly so that's what he mention if I run the same code
on local machine my application will crash right now because.
Desktop doesn't support hardware badminton let's actually still go and run it.
So, I still go and run this application and let's see what we expected is correct.
So, my application...
Going click on appetizers.
...application crashed with type node exception
saying that this type does not exist on desktop if I go and...mobile it will work
fine right so how we're going to go and
six this site how we can go and use the hardware...or any other capability which
are specific to a device family and still maintain a single application package that
works across all device famine this is we are the concept of adaptive
...content I'm sure many of...must have already used reflection
...dot net right and what we have done in windows
...is essentially implemented reflection like api as part of an
...platform itself so that these api the
...on for dotted develop of your csharp and vb for
cplus-plus and even for javascript right let's go and use these adaptive...
To do that...and if check and save windows.
Dot foundation dot metadata on
dot api information top and here you can see
they are different methods implemented you can use a to check for
a particular type of particular...particular property
on method and this case we're just going to go and use is type present so again
dot develop...the you need to positive string for the type that you are checking...just do that.
And, add this into if check.
And, then.
And,...striped here.
And, once you've done...that let's go...set couple of great points.
And, run this...again...local machine.
Click on appetizer...big pointers...I go...fn that
check fields because it tells desktop runtime doesn't support
harvard on this type does not exist...even does not hold up if I press
...five again my application is actually working right
so the application...working because you have written
a adaptive code to actually check for the presence of a particular type when you're running
application if I go and run the same application now.
...emulator.
Should not take more...couple of seconds to...actually go and run...ok and
...working emulator I can go...click on appetizer in this case if
I press fn it returns true so my even handlers
now hooked up now if I press back?
...the even call back and now I can go in...couple of lines of code
...can go back framed...go back and...the navigation.
So, that's the adaptive code for-you so let's actually...dec.
So, we talked about actuation is decays we talked about adaptive code and again
...adaptive api
...located on the windows foundation metadata dot api information you can go
in explore and use some of these to actually trial the capabilities which are specific to a...family.
I'm not going to go and talk about indeed like anything about the adaptive ui but,
example team has done a lot of...work to allow you to actually go in design the
you layoff application based on different phone factors right and
...and how to any are going to do a deep dive on this to model and kind of
they will explain how we should think about all these devices are we should think about found
form factors and what a different reasons anal
...introduced different ways of using adaptive two goes which I integrated
a part of visual state manager to an extent that you can actually going to create totally different
download files and load them into a based on the devices that...running on so
it's a pretty interesting topic and if you are interested in adaptive ui
the strongly recommend you to go and at...this chechen and they will be covering address in-depth?
Now let's talk a little bit about card party actuation is decays ex-change and as the case have
been a critical component for windows platform...
Windows eight windows eight-point one windows...point one
the lot-of actuation is decays that...out...of is develop...using and it's a common
v for developers...coding components with other users and
developers right flaw university windows platform.
We will support referencing existing windows eight-point one actuation is educates
...your universal projects so if you have an existing windows...decay
...can be a behaviors educate that...microsoft ships...can be at third-party another
as decay like tolerate dev express and, you can just go and reference the existing windows eight-point
annexation...in your universal project and use that.
The windows phone eight-point annexation...decay is currently not supported we did
some analysis and found that and most of the cases there was a backing identical windows ape on
one actuation is...so we didn't see a gap in the scenario so we have not supportive windows
...on one actuation educate but this is
a point where I would love to get some feedback if you see...ashish...is
...which is...on windows eight-point one platform that we should think about supporting and please
send-me the feedback and I would have a contact information and we'll try to look into that.
So,...for windows a
...actuation instigate let's go and take a look could do a quick demo for that as well
as you do that I'm going to go and use blend?
In blend so, the way of for adding refers to the actuation educate again I
will go and say...reference if I go to extensions you will see the
behaviors as detailed studio and I don't know if you can see that behind but...up
...that's coming from windows eight-point one location so this is actually windows eight-point one actuation as
decay that are being shown in the context...universal windows platform and you can go and use them
...will try adding a reference if the show you a small warning
icon just to indicate that is not targeting universal
platform but this targeting windows eight-point one...the different platform you can still goal and
add this once you've added the difference
...in blend you can see the behaviors right here in the assets panel
on if...not concept give the concept of behaviors it's a pretty
good concept it's allows adding interactivity if you
...used by designers to add interactivity without actually going
...writing code so let's assume that if I want to go and vid up my
bad button in my application I can use behaviors to do that without writing
codes how you can do that is basically...go and use
even trigger behavior and drag-and-drop it on the...but...my application.
Once have dragnet if you're going to the properties it tells me
that the source for this even trigger behavior is button and even
...says basically dividing up...click event and, that's what the
behavior is doing behind the...behind-the-scenes and if I go and use
the navigate page action I can drag-and-drop and action onto my behavior and I
say the target page is categories right so the recipe page
go back to category and that's pretty much it right so I'm...any line of code
but using behaviors I'm adding interactivity if I go and run this application here.
...appetizerclick on the back but and,
dates back to categories page right so that's the behaviors actuation
is decay and if the windows
...one version that we are using and windows universal application.
If you are using a cplus-plus version of innovate point
...actuation instigate some native actuation...then you have to go and explicitly
...reference to visual studio twenty thirteen cplus-plus the
...framework
for universal windows up and I'll give you why.
The existing crt which was shipped...part of...twenty thirteen doesn't work for
...windows platform because of the changes in the manifest format the package
manifests have significantly change in the use of
windows platform the existing crt does not actually...you...you
...windows platform what we have done here is
...twenty thirteen cplus-plus
crt package it with the new manifest format and then...
again and that's what you will need if you want to use an existing windows eight-point one cplus-plus
exhibition...decay if you don't have as a crt and you're using a native component
you'll get a runtime exception please make sure if you're using any cplus-plus of windows
...on one components references updated crt to be able to use it.
Develop
...can go and build actuation is decays specifically targeting
...windows platform and they can build
is actuation educate and use adaptive code for the platform...so
lot of people here lot of people have authored actualize decays if you're doing that if
you're creating a new actuation educate for us of windows platform you can actually go and right
...code so you...different experience on mobile for your api you can
have a different experience for desktop based on the capabilities that
...device family support but you can maintain a single
actually can use adaptive code to do that also you can go and right adaptive
chord across different versions of universal windows platform right so if they
are multiple versions of windows us...ship you can go and right adaptive
...aggies different versions to using the type
check property checks and everything and still maintain a single actuation is decay that...across all of them.
The ex-change and educates for...windows platform a located on
...decays windows gets...educate folder so if
you're authoring one please make sure you install it in the right location...going to work.
I will briefly talk about the as...manifest dot xml because we
have she's thirteen properties here so if you are...actuation educate this will be useful
to you to mention that target platform is equal to up
...be stanford universal application platform and that's what the
...you to make sure the educate type is
...external the other value for the educate type...platform which
is used by the device foundation is the gave or framework which is used by
framework like crt and stuff like that so in ideal case for third-party actuation
...the...value which...supportive as...type is equal to
...if you don't mention that...by default assume that if
...third-party...as dcmp and as I mentioned before if you're...
actuation is decay these make sure you specify the target platform inversion and the target
platform version properties the min version here will indicate the minimum version
...universe of windows project...develop on needs to be running on to be able to reference
...sdk right and...target platform version means the educate the
you are basically compiling against so we will use
the target platform inversion in visual studio to filter out the in appropriate as decays
for the...as an example if I have a new is...which
...requirement version hundred sixty nine which is shown in the example
and if I'm running a project with a previous version of the os...targeting up and running upgrading a project
which of targeting a previous version of the educate let's say hundred-fifty
...actuation educate will not be even visible in the...dialogue because...to go with friedrich for you
...sure these properties...correctly and...manifested xml?
This is a small fyi.
If you're using vsix
...to go and install your actuation is decay and
you to make sure that you specify the target platform identify and target platform version of windows get
...because vsix...actually uses this property to install the educates
in the right location there's a small fyi if you're using vsix make sure these properties
...set correctly as...installation will not work.
Now let's talk a little bit about new get.
You get has been one of the most popular mechanism for
developers to share their code dealers and components with other developers right
is very popular for universe...platform.
With visual studio two thousand fifteen are
...you get will allow you to go and add refers to an existing windows eight-point
one you get package and you will be able to use that so let's do that let's again go back to bs.
And, in this case I...
Open up simple demo app if I
rightly gone references and go to magnet manage you get packages.
And, I can search for any windows eight-point one you get package less search vocalist...
This is one of the most popular one that's being used right now I can go and install it it's
...a targets windows eight-point one.
I can go and install this new get package in my project.
And, once it's added I can go and build it so if you are if you
all-in-one of the new get packages just targeting windows eight-point one visit
issue doesn't fifteen artsy...go and try to use that in the
context offering universe...windows app and make sure it working appropriately...this totally
a supported scenario and this get the...works you can now go and use the control for
...a part of cholesterol and all expected to work.
At...we will also support
referencing windows for eight-point one you get packages
...your universal windows up the still...still working on it it's not fully they are and health
...not supported as part of your seo to the fifteen...fee but you can
at our dmv will support referencing of windows phone ape on one you get package as
...in your us windows platform also develop...will be able to author
you get packages specifically for the...windows platform at...
If you are interested in this...trying some early preview
...for this and if you are want to go and try some windows...when you get packages here's
my email address send request to me and I will give you the early preview
...you get that you can go and try and see if the scenario works for you.
Now let's talk a little bit about...
As a develop all...as an enterprise.
What are the biggest thing?
That is important for the development and deprive is to understand how
the application of actually being used right which
features in the application are being used by the...by the
...site which...the specific features we are developers are spending maximum
amount of time in the application and these kind of telemetry data hell's
the enterprise and develop...to actually go and make the right investments...versus the right
...application they should...focus on to be able to actually get better
rating and...the ratings and they are different elementary engine that exist
...and for...up...be using app
...sites so every university windows app...by default will have an app insight
experience integrated as part of it and without even writing
...single-line of additional code.
That the app insights will tell you the number of users for your application number of
...for application this specific views of a number the
...for the different views which are being used in your application if you have crashes in your app
if we give you this...information about those crashes and all the real-time usage
...application which country is your application is being used on what kind
of devices app is running on what are the resolution for these devices all the information you
will get it for free without even writing a single line of code using app
insights so that's actually a...a quick demo of that.
So, for that I'm going to...use
michael book application again his map the two different ways you could integrate
up and sites the one-way is when you're creating a project you have a check box
here which tells you to link your existing as your account
critical requirement if you don't do that you will still be getting this data but,
the data will be coming from the store portal you will have to go to store and see
what kind of data update...how the user data and crashes and stuff like that but if you like a
much more detailed view about the app and size data you should probably have a as
...account and use that to automatically link your project with
...as your account and use up...if you already have an application like I have cycle
book and you can write click on the project...ad telemetry app
insights to the project when I click on this?
Is...basically ask me to...so I'm just going to go and provide measure credentials?
And, once it added it showing with the list of as your applications I have and I
will select the...which is the application and go
and add this up so at this point of your
...adding a bunch of new get packages for app
...sites are into the application itself.
that's pretty much it just to show you what exactly the code we are using for app
...you can go and open up adverts...cs and you will see a telemetry
...which is ms-dot app...telemetry
...and that is just initialized in the application object maps pretty much it now
let's go and run this application on local machine.
Let's go and can...need all these?
Big points.
...application invokes now if I go back here and, I bring up the output window.
...the output window you'll see specific app insights event which are
being sent from my project to the app insights of using
happens isometrics...also here in visual studio it actually showing
me that they were three different app insights event which was
sent for this project in this execution I can go and click on this.
And, it'll automatically open up the as you...for me.
So, each a most in should...you open
up the application if that doesn't happen you can go and browsing open up your application.
this is a...application v associated with...studio using app and sized
...conservation and now here...just telling me that they have...user
from application me and my team who are working on this app there have been fifty-one
...for this application...a hundred different page views if I
...specific one it will go and drill down into the data when I click on
the page views it tells me exactly all the details that they've nineteen unique
...page and what exactly number...views and everything for each page is directly tells you get
to that information if you if you run into any crashes you will see the crashes
...for example, if choose me that they've...argument null exception in
my code and you can go and see which kind of forces that was running in what kind of devices that
...is where this crash was happening and get that data directly here using app insights?
If you go down
...you'll see the devices...app is running on sort...to forty-four
and sixty-two is my laptop which I'm using right now and it tells me that I'm running windows ten
...build and these are the different resolution that I've used for my application
and also if you goal the below it tells you even
the diagnostic events so if you click on this delta every event that app
insight has collected fire application and it'll take a little bit
...is all the page views and everything it basically collects and kind of shows you how
exactly this is exactly what we did right now is for twenty-nine to forty-three pm
just click on the recipe as data is already populated in app and sites
...so all this information and elementary data...you can get
...windows app without even writing a
single line of code using apple sites and using the default project complex if you have a question.
It uses the data on which...to.
Yes,or
...single collections of the data I have to...with that I
don't know whether you can opt out of that are how that works but I can follow-up that as a follow-up question.
If it does happen what about if you want to go and you add
some custom telemetry right if you want to go in say unattractive on event I want to
track my own telemetry points you can easily do that as well so, for example,
in this application let's go and...some telemetry even.
Do that I will go and say ...book?
Dot up and I've already create digital
metric lined so I can use that as...dot...event.
And, the document api...I will possum
...string of which event I want to go interact so let's say I'm going to track...navigated to.
then it takes a additionally...possum additional data so I'll path a new dictionary.
here I would pass the additional data...let's see categories.
Because we are tracking which specific categories wasp clicked by the u up
the most popular category and I will positive category that the developer has
...using parameter dot to...
Close this I need to...the...and affect.
Well, I'm probably missing.
So, that's pretty much it...go and run this application again.
Now let's go and click on a category let's say let's.
Convex...individual portal.
And, go back to the application.
And, here just telling me all the custom events that I'm tracking
...using on navigate to for cracking the events.
And, if I go to the diagnostic search as well it should
...has populated issued...with...even that rajesh fired and this is
...to forty-eight pm it tells me the customer event on...to was fired
...categories was bread and the application development so it's like just
was a single-line afford I was able to hook up my ...custom event using the app
...and you can see its get issues in within a thirteen-fifteen
seconds it gets populated in the...even less than like fifteen twenty seconds get
...portal so that's one thing I would strongly recommend if you care about adding telemetry
...app...size and try using this for...us lap.
So, we...already look at a custom events one final thing I want to go and talk about
is the how you should think about if you already building and existing windows eight-point one of windows phone
eight-point one application how you should think about building a new windows universal
...right and there's a couple of different proposals which I think...develop I can think about
...first proposal if you already have an existing application I am pretty sure that you want
to go and maintain those existing applications to target the existing device windows
...and window...device.
...you can do is you can go and add a new universal project right and
this universal project will be for all windows ten divisive that you want to target you can use
adaptive poured to go and check for device specific capabilities and right
codec is that.
You can use adaptive ui that you can go and talk about if you
...learning one-in-ten chechen but you can use adaptive ui to have the
form factors and to make sure you have the right design and running on the right form
facto and you can use shared projects when...components
portable class libraries and dls...the code between all different versions
...can use all them to share corbin...that one-one windows phone equal one...universal project
...this solution you are basically maintaining three different packages...of...that
...windows forty-eight point one and one for the universal package that target all windows ten device.
Now if you going care about specifically about creating a package which is
a specific to of windows ten device family an example
because some constraints you want a specific package to go form windows mobile...different package
to go on rest of the devices you can still do that to do it you will go
and, again, create a new universal project in your value-added
...is a project your solution you would open up the manifest file and
chains the target device family from windows dot universal to
windows dot mobile site and then specify the min version and a
...tested value for windows dot mobile device family
and these values will be published by windows on msdn so you will goal
do msdn and you will see what other current versions of...mobile that are
...the market use that values and
...manifest file and then your package which is going to be created
...only be applicable for windows mobile device family and will not be applicable for
...like desktop riled unixbox if...going target wrestler devices you can create yet
another windows universal project which is targeting for rest of the divisive and then you shared projects
...components and dls to share the code between them so in this case I'm
building to packages for targeting windows...one of the universal
...that goes to xbox coyote and every other device and there's one package which
is specifically being built for windows dot mobile
devices right so when these packages go to store if a consumers downloading
our app and he's running mobile the store will automatically push the mobile version of
your application package if is running on desktop the store will push
the desktop version other windows are universal version of the application packets to the device the
...is already capable of doing that that's the way you will be able to
author package specific to a device family?
These
...resources I already talked about windows samples in on the get tab also
that for developers assistant you can go...downloaded directly from
...have a dev assistant and go and try it to get some sample code
...itself and uniting code.
Finally the registrations one of the key
...that we're going to we are doing for universe of windows platform
is using dot net native right and the that making you dot net
...a default experience for windows than applications they
are lot-of implications on the developer workflow itself to have a deep dive of how
exactly dot tentative works only my manager is going to basically
...tomorrow on ad strongly recommend you guys to go and at
induction because it's going to...the...exactly should think about dot net native
...building...up you also have another
session on sample tools are he's going to talk about more about what I've actually
got a new tools and new profiling tools that we have enabled...to support
...platforms a couple of other interesting issues the adaptive you I already talked about which is being done by
tim and finally the seven forty-one...and the sam jar one on friday
we'll go and explain what exactly the migration process for windows eight-point one to
...project we don't have an automatic
upgrade experience in visual studio for moving our existing windows
...one of into forty-point one application to universal project so he's going to go and deep
dive of how exactly what are the api changes one of
the manifest changes how you structure project and, going to detail of that so
...definitely commend you to go in it and attrition as well.
If you have any questions and happy to...right now have
...handle and email write-up data isd if you have mikes can we get the
...for the for the questions?
And, if you half-time please evaluate decision your feedback
is support important and help us improve thanks for taking time to attend
...evaluated and now I can answer any questions that people have.
If you have...for.
Because...
Pardons...I would expect them to be continually support average...not heard that
...this continue prisms butthis is outside my team so I...have to follow of
...at least not heard the applying to unsupported yep.
So, the data gets pop so,
the question is what happens if the app inside...the client is not really connected I think so
what their mechanism is that the collected and deleted push it and up so I
that I would expect that to be the...that's the key that...collect the data later on...
And, references...the source code okay.
...let's actually going to look at it.
So, right...using dot net frameworks open five-point-one and the
...framework itself is kind of evolving right now with all open-source and avi...also thinking about how
...to actually big dot net framework so that it actually can...a muscle faced a faster
cadence so there's still a little bit of a evolution going for dot net framework but right now
it's using four-point-five...one it's possible that at rem we
baking that into like one...thing that you're looking into is it possible to break the
...framework into a set of new get packages...can go and
reference so there's going to be core set but if you want to go and user specific new we are
...api might have...sununu get packages that actually goes and that's what it.
This is basically thing
...application that's what it's a it's basically targeting a dot net framework this is a
behaviors educate which is a third-party actualize decay that...in my demo for using
behavior right these are the mobile actually...decay is the platform
actualize...because I want to use the hardware back but and that's what is being used for
...and then these are all the new get packages which are being used for app
and sayce to actually collect the data and...your photos...you these all app insights are the
you get packages the app insights...used users for collecting...metric.
And, this is a another you get package that I'm using for parsing my data sample data
...in the application that the new does jason.
It's basically...it's a universal application that...that's...yeah,
this is because it's a universal application that the...showing it think that's on...
Okay,
I can give the...answer and when he was going to go...dive into it...give you a short on
for here if you look into this we actually don't have any cpu any longer
supported in the managed applications so the only you have to actually go
and indicate...the manage application there's no any cpu they are going to be exited
...on which is true for cplus-plus when you ability your application and when you building an application
packets you have to specifically target...if you're building a library
because still...any cpu library that...just go and when you get
a diffusion application package vision the configuration of that application package it will go and build
...that so yes?
So, the question is how it works is basically when you go so,
when you build your...you go and upload your package right...when you upload the package it's
...beggars dot net native?
That will get...into cplus-plus
...issue which is dot net data and you go and upload your package.
The package we contain all the three configurations when the other part of vegetable process viewed build all the three packages
for you and you will upload all three to the store and
...the devices that are running regarding this tool will push the right configuration
...the device.
...to you again this is something that
...tomorrow as part of the content data...
Samoa...samoa.
Costs the.
Universal would be interesting jeopardize a time in a configuration
...not in...with its own...and the custom.
...possibility...box I would like to have some of the
...of going wpf.
So, it's the death something...so ...
Note you have you can do
side loading today as well so for enterprise that I've so if you have to probably
...better question for...clinic and app model...backside
loading works today on windows it on one as well and that is going to be supported for you
...windows platform as well so there's all absolutely is...that you can go inside load and application
you don't have to use windows store...application of how exactly that will
...works...something that you shun follow-up with andrew clinic he's how layer and I'm pretty sure
...talk actually...was the part of it but side loading is different is a...platform?
Yeah, but, restricts, yeah,...yeah.
Now...going to be supported and...defer check with underpinning I'm pretty show
...you often I should be differently work I don't see any...not fights...thank you.
So, right...it's targeting...
five-point-one so that's the aps at the stadium but again.
I can show you something cool which
if I can do it quickly.
One thing that we are looking at is that the
...mentioning is we are looking if when you go so,
let me actually...create a new project...regardless used as well.
...one of the things that we are looking at is how the evolution of
document will happen right so if go darkness...story for dot net as its
...the part of the os...net runtime...shipment os
individuals and when you go and device via basically tie up to windows schedule but we
are looking the way that how we can go in a reader dot net api front-ends keep shipping you
api without actually being...windows itself right so one of the
we're looking at is using the new get packages so here if you see when you
creator demo app and you go to the packages are you see some packages which are
installed by default one of the packages it-system numeric vector four-point-two this
is actually dot net api right and you create a project
...go and...new get package because the expected to be popular enough if we added
lot-of developers will be using it but think about it if the are more new dot net api
is you will have and abilities...on the project say manage new...package and go and...
find that id...you want to goal use addresses to it and start using it because it's new
good...part of your application itself it's gets
...part of application it says that if dot net...devices some of
...you will not be broken right and if you want to use a new appear as you go and...
the new version of dot net you get package and bailey's that so this is the
plan that we're still working on it it's not like super concrete that we can go and say yes this is the
final plan but we have taken the steps to go into that direction and one of the step is basically shipping
system reflective avenue get package...automatically difference in the part of applicant?